[{"id": "5fe6aaf520565ad31a57c822", "question": "Who was the Supreme Commander of the German Navy from 1943 to 1945?", "answer": "Admiral Karl Dointz (also spelled Doenitz)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb63", "question": "In what European country is the headquarters for the World Health Organization?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4c4000d154d7af00b8d0", "question": "Sir Mix-a-Lot's song \"Baby Got Back\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "I Like Big Butts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ccf7a10b37b32637bdc44bf", "question": "What is it called when the liquid vapor pressure equals to the pressure of the gas above it?", "answer": "Boiling Point", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf62", "question": "What year was the Intel Pentium processor introduced?", "answer": "1993", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab972286faa38a764be526", "question": "Which car manufacturer was the first to include seat belts as a standard feature in their vehicles?", "answer": "Saab", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba08", "question": "Whose street name during his days as a juvenile delinquent was \"Detroit Red\"?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a67b90aac110e416707e", "question": "In \"Alice in Wonderland\", who did Alice see taking tea under a tree?", "answer": "Mad Hatter and March Hare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "595242c7736d4be723796b65", "question": "What color was Oscar the Grouch before he was green?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aa2501dd7bf43be5e758", "question": "\"Cohen\" is Hebrew for what?", "answer": "Priest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f77", "question": "Which American author wrote \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Herman Melville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc9", "question": "Who is the Norse god of verility, prosperity, and sun?", "answer": "Frey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aebb", "question": "Who was the first man to swim the English channel?", "answer": "Matthew Webb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c8", "question": "Who owned the detective agency in the TV show \"Remington Steele\"?", "answer": "Laura Holt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ae", "question": "Who signed off his radio show by saying \"Keep your feet on the ground and keep reaching for the stars\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e45", "question": "What fictional island is constantly at war with Blefuscu over the correct way to eat a boiled egg?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ba", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Costa Rica and Honduras?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3eb0d38e4e5d4832e6318", "question": "What name was given to the west wind by the Greeks?", "answer": "Zephyrus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba8", "question": "What 1975 Oscar-winning film features the sadistic Nurse Ratched?", "answer": "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a3b3cf93664eb10486bf", "question": "Who created the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Terry Moore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd71", "question": "Who condensed milk for first time in the US in 1856?", "answer": "Gail Borden, Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f86a01dd7bf43be5e842", "question": "Where were U.S. coins with an \"O\" on them minted?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d22", "question": "Patty Duke won an Oscar in 1963 for portraying what popular author?", "answer": "Helen Keller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ec2b14943630d44e5be228c", "question": "Who started the vision for the long-established fashion for the Kentucky Derby races?", "answer": "Col. Meriwether Lewis Clark Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012197663c99d48cd169af9", "question": "What is it called when a bottle of champagne is open with a sword?", "answer": "Sabering", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae08", "question": "Which New England state was an independent republic for 14 years before joining the union?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a038", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", who unknowingly financed the publication of Peter's erotic novels?", "answer": "Carter Pewterschmidt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a2ec6c0f9723ab15cb48", "question": "Who was the first Roman emperor?", "answer": "Augustus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76697eec85e375820b284", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic was known as the \"Bread Basket of the Empire\"?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600240c94be4723ccac22168", "question": "In Tom Clancy's Jack Ryan novels, Jack graduates from what college?", "answer": "Boston College", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a007", "question": "What city's music scene gave us R.E.M., Danger Mouse, and the B-52s?", "answer": "Athens, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa7", "question": "Who painted \"The 3rd of May\"?", "answer": "Francisco de Goya", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596761c92b59efe0e9417ea6", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e1", "question": "What is the name of the bar that Homer Simpson frequents?", "answer": "Moe's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909d", "question": "Who was the Greek god of harvest and agriculture?", "answer": "Demeter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a4", "question": "What does the equation E=mc2 represent?", "answer": "Mass-energy equivalency", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b342", "question": "Who patented the safety razor in 1895?", "answer": "King Gillette", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b5749076251badbeac3", "question": "For what does NAACP stand?", "answer": "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe655b3ae7e414034b5aeb8", "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes was dedicated to which god?", "answer": "Helios", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cbc0877e98cb97778a1e", "question": "In which country is the Casa Rosada?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d5", "question": "Which band is known in Spain as U-Dos?", "answer": "U2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c2a32b316f4693fb67a2", "question": "A task that has zero chance of success is known as what?", "answer": "Fool's Errand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd82178d0de9af39e9d46a6", "question": "What is the largest contiguous land empire in history?", "answer": "Mongol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a485", "question": "The island of Madeira belongs to which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67b", "question": "What bay does the San Mateo bridge cross?", "answer": "San Francisco Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acda", "question": "Which former American president was also a Nobel laureate and a Princeton professor?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af2581cb63e5727cf5a4845", "question": "What popular toy brand did McDonald\u2019s start offering as a prize with their Happy Meal in 1983?", "answer": "Hot Wheels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b2604fda37788a9a1db9", "question": "Ouagadougou is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e80482de59ea584496fea5", "question": "What is the name of the family whose Dalmatians were stolen in the novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "The Dearly's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c5", "question": "Who produced two booklets for \"Comic Relief\" under the names Newt Scamander and Kennilworthy Whisp?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba1a6874c93a3298b2129", "question": "What year did Jimmy Carter assume office as the 39th President of the United States?", "answer": "1977", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbf806ce05a3942286f00", "question": "In the television series \"Magnum P.I.\", Magnum often wore a ball cap for which sport's team?", "answer": "Detroit Tigers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde2", "question": "What Georgetown star was the first player to be chosen by an NBA draft lottery winner?", "answer": "Patrick Ewing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f91", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Turning Point\"?", "answer": "Leslie Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636de7967692ea851899b0", "question": "What is the name of Rascal Flatts\u2019 10th studio album?", "answer": "\"Back To Us\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25e", "question": "What year was rapper MC Hammer born?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b71f", "question": "What country had, at one time, a female \"Santa\" called La Befena?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a5", "question": "What is the Japanese name for Japan?", "answer": "Nippon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c365a815febcc896f9266", "question": "By what name is the reed pipe of the bagpipes known?", "answer": "Chanter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Krusty the Clown's real full name?", "answer": "Herschel Shmoikel Pinchas Yerucham Krustofsky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a522", "question": "How many neighbors does Lesotho have?", "answer": "Only 1", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b411", "question": "What year did Mauritius gain its independence from Britain?", "answer": "1968", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa0d", "question": "Mount Teide is the highest mountain in which country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a95", "question": "What late 1980s ABC TV show was the first entertainment program to film an episode in Moscow?", "answer": "Head of the Class", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff25b8031a458464a93c478", "question": "In what year was the McDonald's Happy Meal created?", "answer": "Originally fielded in 1977 and ultimately released nationwide in 1979", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6012195a63c99d48cd169af8", "question": "How many bricks were used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "10 million", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe526241bf59ab7d2e380f5", "question": "What is the longest event at the Olympics?", "answer": "Race walk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd6", "question": "Why were the earliest English umbrellas nicknamed \"Robinsons\"?", "answer": "For Robinson Crusoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afbb", "question": "Which former US president was a Peanut Farmer?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bc", "question": "What nationality was Roald Dahl?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaac", "question": "In which country is the Monza Motor Racing Circuit?", "answer": "Italy\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff66dfe52a821ff76ae8b19", "question": "What philosophical tradition is associated with Jean-Paul Sartre?", "answer": "Existentialism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c864", "question": "What pitcher lent his name to ulnar collateral ligament reconstruction?", "answer": "Tommy John", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60121c5063c99d48cd169b15", "question": "The Norman Rockwell Museum is home to the artist\u2019s last what?", "answer": "Studio -- Of the approximately 20 studios Rockwell used over the course of his life, the Norman Rockwell Museum is the last.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ee", "question": "On what continent is Mt. Vesuvius?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79c", "question": "What is the name of Neptune's largest moon?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f91d01dd7bf43be5e84b", "question": "A shaving commercial featuring which two famous people launched the whole Super Bowl commercial phenomenon?", "answer": "Farah Fawcett and Joe Namath", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c306", "question": "Which is longer, a python or a boa constrictor?", "answer": "A python", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600243494be4723ccac22194", "question": "Humbert Humbert is the protagonist and narrator of which controversial novel?", "answer": "\"Lolita\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aced", "question": "Who was Jimmy Carter's vice president?", "answer": "Walter (Fritz) Mondale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bb", "question": "At the 1996 Olympics, what American tied Mark Spitz's lifetime record of nine golds?", "answer": "Carl Lewis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ec4fda37788a9a1db4", "question": "Which once-common disease was also known as the \"Great white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8c", "question": "What occupation traditionally referred to its apprentices as \"devils\"?", "answer": "Printers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c010", "question": "What does lager literally mean in German?", "answer": "Storeroom, or warehouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66479a5bfecdd737e0855", "question": "Who was the first US president to be heard on the radio?", "answer": "Warren Harding", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b093", "question": "What large amphitheater in Rome was opened to showcase gladiator combat?", "answer": "The Colosseum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a367", "question": "What US city had the first subway?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0da", "question": "Which Latin word is used to express the meaning \"word for word\"?", "answer": "Verbatim", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5b", "question": "Port Vila is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926f", "question": "How much does the Academy Award statue weigh?", "answer": "8.5 pounds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339054", "question": "What was the name of Sherlock Holmes' intelligent brother?", "answer": "Mycroft", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f7209a9e54d890926f6e9", "question": "What is the biggest desert in Australia?", "answer": "Great Victoria Desert -- Located in Western and South Australia, it is home to several nature reserves and a national park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6562bae7e414034b5aec2", "question": "Which ancient civilization created zodiac signs?", "answer": "Babylonia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99aef21a8909e5c332d26", "question": "Who was John Lennon married to?", "answer": "Yoko Ono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b685", "question": "What insulates the ice cream to prevent it from melting in the hot dish \"Baked Alaska\"?", "answer": "Meringue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f0b401dd7bf43be5e801", "question": "What was candy corn originally called?", "answer": "Chicken Feed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008a56cf842fa4c4ba968f", "question": "What nationality was Johnny Weissmuller?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14a", "question": "In 1998, John Glenn returned to space aboard which space shuttle?", "answer": "Discovery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5db03e6caa1c9af2684d79a4", "question": "What is the common name for CH3COOH?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fc", "question": "Off the coast of what continent will you find the Strait of Magellan?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a7", "question": "Which artist's \"Impression Sunrise\" gave its name to the whole impressionist movement?", "answer": "Claude Monet's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a98", "question": "What early rock and roll pioneer's real first and middle name was Charles Hardin?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a53690aac110e4167072", "question": "What types of beer are usually used in the making of a Black and Tan?", "answer": "Pale lager and stout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd5", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"canyon\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad44", "question": "What is the maiden name of former first lady Betty Ford?", "answer": "Bloomer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a167", "question": "Who played Sarah Conner in the 1991 film \"Terminator 2: Judgment Day\"?", "answer": "Linda Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010ca540775fa611bce67f7", "question": "What mythical beast suffers from a condition known as lycanthropy?", "answer": "Werewolves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323315bf195a31e15d7397", "question": "Blitz, Boondock, Bristol, Scrunge and Squop are terms used in what game?", "answer": "Tiddlywinks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a828", "question": "In which US city is the United States Naval Academy located?", "answer": "Annapolis, Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d77", "question": "What was formed by the five robot lions of the planet Arus?", "answer": "Voltron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20ef431a458464a93c42c", "question": "Who wrote the ballet \"The Creatures of Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0d", "question": "What year was comedian Jon Stewart born?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ace301dd7bf43be5e771", "question": "What company created Mr. Pibb?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb4437e83c707845b2118", "question": "Water deer have what unique feature?", "answer": "Tusks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe52f451bf59ab7d2e38113", "question": "What direction does the Statue of Liberty face?", "answer": "Southeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbce", "question": "In the card game Bridge, what is considered the highest of the four suits?", "answer": "Spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf65", "question": "What is Wales' national dish called?", "answer": "Cawl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b8b9364247bf200fb883", "question": "In the 1983 film \"National Lampoon's Vacation\", where were the Griswold's headed on their cross country trip?", "answer": "Walley World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab85", "question": "Who was the first person to reach the North Pole in 1909?", "answer": "Robert Peary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f71a8a9e54d890926f6e3", "question": "Where is the International Space Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Alamogordo, New Mexico -- It is located within the New Mexico Space Museum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b78d", "question": "Cha dao is the art of what?", "answer": "Making tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a9", "question": "What color appears in the middle of a rainbow?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b33601dd7bf43be5e7aa", "question": "Which popular fruit can only be grown one at a time?", "answer": "Pineapple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b41c06d333868d34d6e0", "question": "Who was the famous botanist who traveled with Captain Cook on his first voyage?", "answer": "Joseph Banks", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ec", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1984 film \u201cStarman\u201d?", "answer": "Jeff Bridges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b639", "question": "What brand of seasoning was named after a famous prime rib restaurant?", "answer": "Lawry's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb69e25dad637d903c884b", "question": "In which country will you find a peninsula called \"Land\u2019s End\"?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958c", "question": "What song did Wayne and Garth listen to on their way to the doughnut shop in the movie \"Wayne's World\"?", "answer": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cf", "question": "What country was policed by the Blackshirts for almost 25 years?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339341", "question": "Who is Kyle's brother on the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Ike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1e", "question": "Which popular artist was born Gordon Matthew Thomas Sumner?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd667a0a5bfecdd737e086b", "question": "What condition is singultus better known as?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53f", "question": "How many feet in a fathom?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323331bf195a31e15d7398", "question": "What is the capital of Botswana?", "answer": "Gaborone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90a", "question": "What major river runs through St. Petersburg?", "answer": "Neva", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf7", "question": "The feet of the infamous Pez dispenser were not added until what year?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067a93ff9c0647b50a805b", "question": "What date did the United Kingdom European Union membership referendum took place on?", "answer": "June 23, 2016", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cc", "question": "Concord is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5922038aa4edfd43a087ade3", "question": "What shapes are used in a Venn diagram?", "answer": "Circles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b326", "question": "Who was the wife of King Ahab?", "answer": "Jezebel of Sidon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc5666ce05a3942286f3d", "question": "The book \"I, Robot\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d8", "question": "What was the first man-made satellite put into orbit?", "answer": "Sputnik I", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa4", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eaf96f83302ff91e46494", "question": "What are juvenile goats called?", "answer": "Kids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339436", "question": "What kind of car does Lester buy in the 1999 movie \"American Beauty\"?", "answer": "Firebird", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728cc86bcd28c11938328c", "question": "Dover is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fcd", "question": "The word \"Cyberspace\" appeared for first time in which William Gibson publication?", "answer": "Burning Chrome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b95", "question": "Who played the role of Basil Exposition in the three \"Austin Powers\" movies?", "answer": "Michael York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d95de08b8581f80b092a4", "question": "Which day of the week did January 1, 2017, fall on?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c055", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iran?", "answer": "Common nightingale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c12", "question": "What year saw the debut of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8a", "question": "What\u2019s the Hungarian word for red pepper?", "answer": "Paprika", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60023f054be4723ccac22161", "question": "As of 2020, what was the name and breed of the tallest dog ever?", "answer": "A Great Dane named Zeus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe908a101dd7bf43be5e886", "question": "What vitamin does E. coli produce?", "answer": "K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2a", "question": "Who is Larry Hagman's mother?", "answer": "Mary Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a2c56c0f9723ab15cb46", "question": "Which volcano had the most powerful eruption of the 20th century?", "answer": "Novarupta volcano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a998", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Fuji\"?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b938", "question": "What decade gave us the first ATM?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600b86961d8c1817608d53e6", "question": "What kind of person shall not be honored on a US postal stamp, according to the USPS and the Citizen\u2019s Stamp Advisory Committee?", "answer": "A living person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca72", "question": "What is measured in fathoms?", "answer": "Depth of water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339123", "question": "Which artist created the appearance of Babar the Elephant?", "answer": "Jean de Brunhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b2", "question": "On which fictional street does Freddy Kruger live out a nightmare?", "answer": "Elm Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390dd", "question": "In the Winnie-the-Pooh stories what is Kanga\u2019s baby called?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f42", "question": "Who created the character of Yogi Bear?", "answer": "William Hanna and Joseph Barbera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea83c7ff048f679a45ac2b", "question": "What is the largest human organ?", "answer": "Skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0af", "question": "Who was Al Gore's running mate in the 2000 presidential election?", "answer": "Joe Lieberman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b565", "question": "What is the most expensive spice in the world?", "answer": "Saffron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c7e1fbde8045e48466c9", "question": "How many stomachs does a llama have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e5f11e3d274615ecf51453c", "question": "\"Oscitation\", is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Yawning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf13", "question": "What colour caps do the Australian cricket team wear?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab48c0b8cce1e6fda7048", "question": "What is the main ingredient in falafel?", "answer": "Chickpeas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0adf0e662d71a53650fb5", "question": "Who became famous for painting New Mexico landscapes from her Model A Ford?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keeffe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae01", "question": "King Zog ruled which country?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e48", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Naked Gun\"?", "answer": "O. J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ca", "question": "What is the standard glass drinkware for the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Cocktail glass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59f", "question": "What colorful name is often applied to a sequoia?", "answer": "Redwood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffe4bcb47818f5674af01b3", "question": "What is the name of the book the movie \"Goodfellas\" is based on?", "answer": "\"Wiseguy: Life in a Mafia Family\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e17", "question": "What French Wave director plays the UFO expert in \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Francois Truffaut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ee", "question": "What gland do all mammals have?", "answer": "Mammary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba18c874c93a3298b2127", "question": "Of which US state was Jimmy Carter Governor before he became president?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4a", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d9b02596a59cbdfbd3c9", "question": "What was the first crime Billy the Kid was arrested for?", "answer": "Stealing clothes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f14afe83fe1f2a824c16", "question": "What ancient astrological event is December 25th also associated with?", "answer": "December 25 was the date of the winter solstice on the Roman calendar.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4e", "question": "Angelo Sicilano better know as who?", "answer": "Charles Atlas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca30", "question": "Eczema affects which part of the body?", "answer": "Skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1dd", "question": "What does the term \"A La Carte\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "According to the menu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22c", "question": "Where did Al Capone spend the majority of his 1931 sentence for tax evasion?", "answer": "Alcatraz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f3052145aa2bc17b61b2ac8", "question": "Chisinau is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Moldova", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9af", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Ecuador?", "answer": "Chimborazo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c665", "question": "Who performed the first human heart transplant?", "answer": "Dr. Chris Barnard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f4a0ff048f679a45aac7", "question": "What is the largest object in the asteroid belt that lies between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "Ceres", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a36c9d816e292245c15", "question": "What artist created a stained glass window for the United Nations?", "answer": "In 1964, a 15 by 12 foot stained glass window by\u00a0Marc Chagall\u00a0was donated to the United Nations to commemorate Dag Hammarskj\u00f6ld.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb9", "question": "What is California also known as?", "answer": "The Golden State", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c162", "question": "The Demologos was the first steam powered what?", "answer": "Warship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5e106ce05a3942286e2f", "question": "Which movie\u2019s sequel has the tagline \"Same make. Same model. New mission\"?", "answer": "\"Terminator\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe51e681bf59ab7d2e380e1", "question": "Jambon is the French word for what food?", "answer": "Ham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c08", "question": "What Ernest Hemingway novel is set during the Spanish Civil War?", "answer": "For Whom the Bell Tolls", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde52b6c6c6b019850c9a98", "question": "In Proverbs, when Solomon refers to the lazy, he tells the sluggard to look to what insect for an example?", "answer": "Ant", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65961ae7e414034b5aefe", "question": "Who was the last Filipino general to surrender to the Americans during the Filipino-American war?", "answer": "General Miguel Malvar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca64", "question": "What type of creature is an Orb Weaver?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a0", "question": "How many gallons does a tun barrel typically hold?", "answer": "252", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc0", "question": "What genre is James Brown considered to be the grandfather of?", "answer": "Soul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b726", "question": "What seafood is considered a Christmas favourite in Paris, France?", "answer": "Oysters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b77", "question": "What patriotic anthem composed by Irving Berlin includes the lyrics \"Stand beside her and guide her\"?", "answer": "God Bless America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3ccfc73aa70ea0b70aef", "question": "Which country shares part of its name with its capital?", "answer": "The capital of El Salvador is San Salvador. The city lies below the slopes of the San Salvador volcano, for which it is named.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a3", "question": "Who is known as Lady Soul?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6c", "question": "With which team did Brett Favre start his professional football career in 1991?", "answer": "Atlanta Falcons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9a2cebfabb9c85d8a978", "question": "Which British Prime Minister died in 1965?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6656ca5bfecdd737e085f", "question": "What three vows do Catholic priests take?", "answer": "Poverty, chastity and obedience", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3f0444f0f6af5b06664f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state New Hampshire?", "answer": "Concord", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb0", "question": "Which was the first country to leave the Commonwealth in 1949?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a931", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Haiti?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e0", "question": "In the professional audio industry, what does AES refer to?", "answer": "Audio Engineering Society", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3d", "question": "What is the title object of the 2006 film \"Brick\" a brick of?", "answer": "Heroin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339702", "question": "What name does the Simpsons' dog answer to?", "answer": "Santa's Little Helper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d9", "question": "What body of water separates Alaska from Russia?", "answer": "Bering Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e8", "question": "What year did the Gran Turismo game series first debut?", "answer": "1997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b6", "question": "What is the name of the artist Prince's recording studio?", "answer": "Paisley Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac4", "question": "What early rock pioneer once told an unresponsive audience, \"I hope you all get heart attacks\"?", "answer": "Jerry Lee Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a703", "question": "Which is the smallest state in the US?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a427", "question": "In what country would you find Mount Everest?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ca", "question": "What is the capital of the state of Utah?", "answer": "Salt Lake City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bafc", "question": "The clarinet is a member of what family of instruments?", "answer": "Woodwinds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2f", "question": "What popular figure was assassinated by Sirhan Sirhan?", "answer": "Robert F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6aaa420565ad31a57c81d", "question": "What kind of planes were used in the Doolittle Raid?", "answer": "B-25 bombers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdd69e347d002c297e4f0", "question": "What are affected by Phylloxera?", "answer": "Grapevines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9b", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Raytown?", "answer": "Mama's Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c1", "question": "What country proclaimed the birth of its billionth citizen in 2000?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b7d1364247bf200fb877", "question": "Which Canadian city was originally called Bytown?", "answer": "Ottawa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59068223ff9c0647b50a809a", "question": "Which US Senator was nominated as Hillary Clinton\u2019s vice presidential running mate?", "answer": "Tim Kaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b32368ebf195a31e15d73bc", "question": "An \"omniscient\" person has unlimited what?", "answer": "Knowledge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4b", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Passion of Joan of Arc\"?", "answer": "Renee Maria Falconetti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b069", "question": "What company introduced the first canned ham in the US in 1926?", "answer": "Hormel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe773cceec85e375820b30d", "question": "The Cherokee rose is the state flower of which U.S. state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6b7a3fb6c85e9e634ff4c", "question": "Which comet is visible every 74 to 79 years?", "answer": "Halley's comet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f950fa5fdd6dd25324f6", "question": "What name is given to animals which only eat plants?", "answer": "Herbivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a359", "question": "What is the northernmost Scandinavian country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b34901dd7bf43be5e7ab", "question": "What store was originally called \"Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Best Buy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338881", "question": "What adventure tale introduced: \"Yo-ho-ho, and a bottle of rum!\"", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5901d831709c1c34536e6ea5", "question": "What is the protective coating called that covers chicken eggs when they're hatched?", "answer": "Bloom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a436", "question": "Is Japan closer to the North Pole or the South Pole?", "answer": "North Pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cd40ba5685cf15b733e988b", "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?", "answer": "Somerset", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c0", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure of any animal?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d0", "question": "How many guns does Travis buy in the movie \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "4", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d1", "question": "What month's birthstone places highest on the Mohs scale?", "answer": "April's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f980fa5fdd6dd25324f8", "question": "Who would use a mashie niblick?", "answer": "A golfer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008b35cf842fa4c4ba9696", "question": "What composer wrote the \"Pomp and Circumstance\" marches?", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e96627ccba3ffe45786ec", "question": "In which European country is Tokaj wine produced?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57a", "question": "What popular soft drink was first created in Waco, Texas?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399df", "question": "In the 1991 animated Disney film \"Beauty and the Beast\", what type of enchanted item is Chip?", "answer": "A teacup", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e386fcbed638185eaa22", "question": "What U.S. state is nicknamed \"The Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab92", "question": "What year did Cambodia gain its independence from France?", "answer": "1953", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6b", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Scent of a Woman\"?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d4", "question": "In what US state would you find Area 51?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}]